{
    "id": "0bea6c9306344256a293db388ee3dd74",
    "title": "Subject-Verb Agreement Worksheet",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Neither pleasure nor pain ……………………… to move him.",
            "description": "When we connect two singular nouns with neither/nor, the verb is singular.",
            "answers": [
                "seem",
                "seems"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither the master nor his servants …………………………… present in the barn.",
            "description": "When we connect a singular noun and a plural noun with neither/nor, the verb agrees with the number and person of the noun closest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "No nook or corner ……………………………. left unsearched.",
            "description": "When we connect two singular nouns with or, the verb is singular.",
            "answers": [
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Either you or I ……………………………… mistaken.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with either/or, the verb agrees in number and person with the noun closest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "am"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Neither you nor he ……………………………… right.",
            "description": "When we connect two nouns with neither/nor, the verb agrees in number and person with the noun closest to it.",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "is",
                "am"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "None of them …………………………. arrived.",
            "description": "A singular verb is used after none. ",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "All of his books …………………………. worth reading.",
            "description": "Use a plural verb after all. ",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "She is getting married to Sam, who ………………………… her college mate.",
            "description": "The verb in the relative clause agrees with its antecedent in number and person.",
            "answers": [
                "are",
                "was",
                "were"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I who …………………………….. your patron will never desert you.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "are",
                "am"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "A lot of work ………………………………. to be done.",
            "description": "When a lot of is followed by an uncountable noun, the verb is singular in number.",
            "answers": [
                "need",
                "needs"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "A lot of people ……………………………….. in ghosts.",
            "description": "When a lot of followed by a plural noun, the verb is plural in number.",
            "answers": [
                "believe",
                "believes"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "There ……………………….. been many studies on this subject.",
            "description": "When the noun following there is plural, the verb is plural. ",
            "answers": [
                "has",
                "have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}